<section id="editschedule">
<title>Edit Schedule.</title>
<para>
	Schedules are used to initiate/trigger builds either non-interactively or manually.
</para>
<para id="buildworkdir">
    Each build needs a work directory to checkout the artifacts from VCS repository. Following are
    the rules that Luntbuild uses to construct work directory:
    <orderedlist numeration="arabic">
    <listitem><para>
        Main Luntbuild <emphasis>work directory</emphasis> is used as a root
        of all Luntbuild projects.
    </para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>
        Each schedule allows you to define its work directory. By default, this directory is a subdirectory
 		named using the project name under Luntbuild's top level work directory.
    </para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>
        VCS modules contain source path that is appended after the schedule work directory.
    </para></listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</para>
<para>
    For example if Luntbuild's work directory is <emphasis>/luntbuild-install-dir/work</emphasis>,
    project name is <emphasis>myproject</emphasis>,
    schedule subdirectory is <emphasis>myscheduleworkdir</emphasis>, and VCS source path is <emphasis>source</emphasis>,
    then absolute path of the build's work directory for given schedule is
    <emphasis>/luntbuild-install-dir/work/myproject/myscheduleworkdir/source</emphasis>.
</para>
<para>
    Why is this important? Because of following reasons:
    <simplelist>
        <member>
            The build's work directory can be shared between multiple schedules of the same project. In this case
            the builds of those schedules use the same work directory, thus saving the disk space.
            Luntbuild guarantees that builds that share the same work directory cannot be
            executed at the same time. If first build using the shared work directory starts,
            all additional builds that share the same work directory are entered to the pending
            build queue, and they are executed only after currently executing build finishes.
        </member>
        <member>
            If the build's work directory is not shared with other schedules of the same project,
            contents of the VCS modules for the given project is checked multiple times (to multiple
            work directories), thus consuming more disk space and possibly taking more time
            to checkout the contents of the VCS modules. Advantage of this approach is, that builds
            using different work directories (for the same project) can be executed in parallel.
        </member>
    </simplelist>
</para>
<para id="buildpublishdir">
Each build also uses its publish directory to store the build artifacts like build log and revision log.
Following are the rules that Luntbuild uses to construct publish directory:
    <orderedlist numeration="arabic">
    <listitem><para>
        Main Luntbuild <emphasis>publish directory</emphasis> is used as a root
        of all Luntbuild projects.
    </para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>
        Project name is used to define subdirectory in the main <emphasis>publish directory</emphasis>.
    </para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>
        Schedule name is used to define subdirectory in the project subdirectory.
    </para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>
        Build version string is used to create subdirectory in the schedule subdirectory. This subdirectory
        contains build log <emphasis>build_log.txt, build_log.html, build_log.xml</emphasis>
        and revision log <emphasis>revision_log.txt, revision_log.html, revision_log.xml</emphasis>,
        and two subdirectories <emphasis>artifacts</emphasis> and <emphasis>junit_html_report</emphasis>.
        Subdirectory <emphasis>artifacts</emphasis> can be used by you to store any other additional artifacts,
        subdirectories <emphasis>junit_html_report</emphasis> is used to store results of JUnit testing.
    </para></listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</para>
<para>
    For example if Luntbuild's publish directory is <emphasis>/luntbuild-install-dir/publish</emphasis>,
    project name is <emphasis>myproject</emphasis>,
    schedule name is <emphasis>myschedule</emphasis>, and current build version is <emphasis>myapp-1.2.0</emphasis>,
    then absolute path of the build's publish directory for given schedule is
    <emphasis>/luntbuild-install-dir/publish/myproject/myschedule/myapp-1.2.0</emphasis>.
</para>
<para>To create a schedule, click on Schedules Tab, and click on New Schedule icon in the upper right corner of the tab's frame.</para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>Schedules Editor Tab</screeninfo>
<mediaobject>
    <imageobject><imagedata fileref="images/schedule-editor.jpg" format="JPG" /> </imageobject>
<textobject> <phrase>Schedules Editor Tab</phrase> </textobject>
</mediaobject>
</screenshot>
</section>